# Jonas Felipe Virgilio da Silva

Jundiaí, São Paulo, Brazil



jonas.virgilios@gmail.com



11999772519



linkedin.com/in/jonas-felipe-virgilio-dasilva-5424a05a

# Summary

I am continuously developing my skills in software development and architecture. I'm proactive, results-oriented and focused on productivity and quality.

I'm a team player and enjoy exchanging knowledge and experience, which I believe is a great source for personal and professional growth. I'm constantly studying to improve my skills in design patterns, new frameworks and languages, architecture and DevOps.

I also like taking on and solving challenges.

# **Experience**



## Senior Software Engineer .Net

ESX

Jan 2022 - Present (3 months +)



# 💢 .NET Developer

**ESX** 

Sep 2020 - Jan 2022 (1 year 5 months)

Development of Solutions for Companies in the Fleet Management Segment

Technologies used daily:

- Asp.net Core
- Unity Test used XUnit/NUnit
- Relational DataBase: SQL SERVER
- DB NoSQL: MONGO - Micro-ORM: Dapper
- AZURE (Azure Functions, Service Bus, WebJobs)
- Repository: GitLab
- VSTS



#### .NET Developer

Joit Solutions

Nov 2018 - Sep 2020 (1 year 11 months)

Focused on developing and patching all client applications

Conveyor, across the entire range of transport. I act as a technical key piece,

Windows Services development, APIs, Web systems, and database development

Dice. I am currently working with .Net Framework and .Net Core as the main

programming languages to develop applications, Cloud performances, Data, Security,

#### MVC, applying the SOLID standard

Evolutionary and corrective maintenance of the customers' systems in general.

- Integrations between systems through Rest APIs
- Development of new projects from their conception to implementation in production
- Meeting with clients with the business team to understand the scope and survey/planning of activities developed.
- Analysis of system characteristics to survey business/process flow for analysis of implementations/ modifications and impacts.

## .NET Developer

# Fagron Tech

Jul 2017 - Nov 2018 (1 year 5 months)

I worked as a FullStack developer programming in .Net Core, .Net Framework, and MVC for in projects for Master Pharmacy customers, using technologies such as Entity Framework, Dapper, Data and MVC, WCF, and Web API. Front End with HTML 5, javascript, CSS3 and frameworks like bootstrap, Sass, typescript, angular JS, and development methodology agile (scrum) with Visual Studio Team Foundation and Visual Studio Online

# .NE

# .NET Developer

Freelancer

Sep 2016 - Jul 2017 (11 months)

Atuando com desenvolvimento de websites com .Net/C#

# METALPLAN

#### System Analyst - Protheus

Metalplan Equipamentos Ltda.

Feb 2016 - Sep 2016 (8 months)

Routine Development, Enter Point, TReport, Integreation of Office, Cnab, Workflow

# METALPLAN

#### Analista de Ti

Metalplan Equipamentos Ltda.

Oct 2014 - Feb 2016 (1 year 5 months)

IT analyst focused on ERP Microsiga Protheus

Level 2 and 3 user support

Development of Treport, Entry Points, and Workflow reports

Systems Analysis for Decision Making

Knowledge in Business Rules

Módulos: Administrativos/ Materiais/RH



## **Analista de Sistemas Protheus**

Ingram Micro

Jan 2013 - May 2014 (1 year 5 months)

Atuação com Protheus 11

Análises de Processos e Sistemas: Estoque/Fiscal

Projeto: Kardex Negativo/Cat17

Atividades: Análise de Estoques, Invetários dos anos de 2011/12, Entrega de

Obrigações SPED Fiscal/Sintegra/Gia Módulos: Livros Fiscais/Estoque-Custos

Projeto tem como enfâse o ressarcimento dos valores dos impostos pagos na

compra dos produtos

Desenvolvimento de Querys para tomada de decisão

# **Education**



Postgraduate Course Topics in Information Systems - eScience, Data Processing and Data Processing Technology 2016 - 2018

# Fate: Sorocaba Technological College (FATEC)

Information Technology Management, Information Technology 2007 - 2011

# **Licenses & Certifications**

Data Structure - Python - Coursera Course Certificates
545BCGL6W45X

Programming for Everybody (Getting Started with Python) - Coursera Course
Certificates
PU4MV5S68CGG

- Hadoop Platform and Application Framework Coursera Course Certificates
  58YLAG7EXKG2
- Introdução a Big Data Coursera Course Certificates KDM35WLX8E3J
- Gestão Empresarial com ERP TOTVS TOTVS
- oo Fluência Duolingo em Inglês: Intermediário (estimativa) Duolingo
- Python 3 part 1: Introduction to the new language version Grupo Alura
- Machine Learning: Introdução a classificação com SKLearn Alura 4adb431b-c2ad-4283-a699-f6dacca9bde1

#### Skills

ASP.NET • ASP.NET MVC • Python (Programming Language) • Microsoft SQL Server • CSS • HTML5 • Entity Framework • ASP.NET AJAX • Bootstrap • JQuery